ALESSANDRO BARRETO

DEVELOPER | ENGINEER

ABOUT

Technology enthusiast, proactive and constantly seeking new challenges for personal and professional development. Both graduated in Engineering and Systems Analysis and Development I have 6 years of experience in the market, working in areas such as modeling, development, data analysis and commercial management. I currently work as a software developer in Europe.

KNOWLEDGE

Computing

• Data Analysis

Programming

Web Development

• Comercial Management

• Agile Methodologies

Client Communication

SKILLS

TOOLS

- React
- Next.js
- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- Python
- HTML
- CSS
- SASS
- Node
- 1.000
- Material UI
- Redux
- Context API
- Styled Components
- Express
- GraphQL
- MongoDB
- Jest
- Docker
- Git
- Microsoft Office

LANGUAGES

Portuguese

English

Spanish

00000

00000

00000

CONTACT:

✓ alessandrobarreto1201@gmail.com

(+351) 912 765 320

Lisbon, Portugal

in linkedin.com/in/alessandro--barreto

github.com/AlessandroBarreto

<u>alessandro-barreto.netlify.app/</u>

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Front End Engineer

Farfetch | Abr 2023 - Present

- Front Typescript, HTML, CSS, Figma;
 Frameworks/Libs: NextJS, Styled Components, GraphQL, Redux, Mockserver;
- **Back**: Typescript; Frameworks/Libs: Node, NestJS;
- **Testing**: Jest, React-testing-library, Cypress;
- Devops: Docker, Jenkins, MacOS, Git, GitLab, Postman, Jira, Confluence;
- Scrum.

Full Stack Developer

Aubay | Dec 2021 - Abr 2023

- Front Typescript, HTML, CSS, Figma;
 Frameworks/Libs: NextJS, Theme UI, Styled Components, Context API, Axios;
- Back: Typescript;
 Frameworks/Libs: Node, AWS lambda;
- Testing: Jest, React-testing-library;
- **DB**: Commercetools;
- **Devops**: Docker, AWS, MacOS, Git, Postman, CI/CD, Kibana, Jira;
- Scrum.

Full Stack Developer

J&A Holding | May 2021 - Dec 2021

- **Front** Javascript, Typescript, HTML, CSS, Adobe XD; Frameworks/Libs: React, Angular, React Router, Material UI, Axios;
- **Back**: Javascript, Typescript, Python; Frameworks/Libs: Node, Express, Flask, Selenium, Pandas, Numpy;
- **Testing**: Jest, React-testing-library;
- DB: Mongo;
- Devops: Docker, Google Workspace, Bitbucket, Linux, Windows, Git, Postman;
- Scrum.

EDUCATION

Estacio University

Degree in Systems Analysis and Development | 2020 - 2023

Federal University of Santa Catarina

Degree in Civil Engineering: Sanitation and Environment | 2013 - 2019

REFERENCES

Gilherme Girol

CTO | Sanova Water Management Solutions E-mail: guilherme.girol@sanova.com.br

Lucas Lovato

Software Developer | Clevertech E-mail: Lucas.lovato@clevertech.biz

Sarah Pfaffenzeller

Software Developer | TheoremOne

E-mail: sarahizabelp@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Front End Engineer

Farfetch | Abr 2023 - Present

• I worked on the maintenance, implementation and testing of Farfetch's CMS platform for several world-renowned fashion clients (Ferragamo, Off-White, Reebok, Harrods, Browns etc...). The system was built on a microservices architecture and some of the technologies used were: Next.JS, GraphQL, TypeScript, Redux, Styled Components and Nest.JS. Pipeline and deployment using Jenkins and containerization with Docker. Tests were part of the delivery: unitary and E2E. and the versioning platform was Gitlab. Scrum was the agile methodology applied;

Full Stack Developer

Aubay | Dec 2021 - Present

BMW group client. I worked on the maintenance, implementation and testing for the 3 e-commerce platforms of BMW and MINI
cooper (cars, products and services) in several countries. The main technology used was NextJS with server side rendering, state
management, styled components, testing with jest and AWS ecosystem tools. Commercetools was the platform for creating and
managing products and orders;

Full Stack Developer

J&A Holding | May 2021 - Dec 2021

• I worked with front end tools like Angular and wordpress to maintain the websites of J&A Holding companies. I participated in the construction of several robots using Python, pandas, selenium, requests, HTML and CSS for the processes automation and email campaigns of the company and creation of screens using React, APIs in Node and express for the consumption of these robots, together with MongoDB. Containerization of the applications using Docker, Docker Compose and Linux servers. Construction of the website with the new identity of Fontes Promotora website, using React and covering the desktop and mobile versions;

Front End Developer

Aquarela Advanced Analytics | Mar 2020 - May 2021

I worked on the front end (React) together with the back end to design an internal platform for manage and search projects, stacks, tools and company workers. Then I worked on the front-end of the Fras-le (automotive segment) company's artificial intelligence project, focusing on building screens for data visualization, using React, D3, tests with Jest and Enzyme, documentation of processes and I started experimenting tools like Docker, MongoDB and Python for the back end. Finally, I worked on the construction of an ontology finder plataform using React;

Engineer

Sanova | Mar 2018 - Mar 2020

• I worked with commercial management of a private sanitation system. My tasks were the maintaince, testing and implementation of the company's website using React, HTML and CSS, email sending campaigns with Node and data analysis using excel and python with libraries such as pandas and numpy. I worked also with modeling projects usings engineering softwares;

Intern

Santa Catarina University | Jan 2017 - Jan 2018

• I worked in a project related to recover the water quality of my university. I used python and excel to data analasys, Javascript, HTML and CSS to build simple documents and Microsoft Office to make presentations and documentation.

VOLUNTEERING EXPERIENCE

Tech Mentor

Technovation | Fev 2021 - Abr 2021

• Technovation is an international program that encourages children around the world to learn and apply the skills needed to solve real world problems through technology. I acted as a mentor in a team of 4 children between 12 and 14 years old, participating in workshops, meetings and planning to create an environmental awareness app as a final product of the project.